<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-12-27T10:45:45+00:00</updated><id>https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SSoulSS</title><subtitle>Software product development for healthcare and booking systems.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The “WTF” Moment: When India’s Brokerage Host Met a Tech Titan</title><link href="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/news/podcasts/2025/12/16/wtf-musk-kamath.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The “WTF” Moment: When India’s Brokerage Host Met a Tech Titan" /><published>2025-12-16T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-16T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/news/podcasts/2025/12/16/wtf-musk-kamath</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/news/podcasts/2025/12/16/wtf-musk-kamath.html"><![CDATA[<p>Nikhil Kamath’s podcast People by WTF recently released an episode that quickly circulated across Indian social feeds: a long-form conversation with Elon Musk. The episode blends casual curiosity with philosophical digressions, and it offers several memorable moments that people have been discussing online.</p>

<p>🎧 The vibe</p>

<p>The tone of the conversation felt more exploratory than combative. Kamath, who has a conversational, informal hosting style, allowed Musk space to expand on ideas, resulting in a mix of curiosity, uneven pacing and occasional philosophical asides. The setting and cadence — coffee, long-form back-and-forth — produced moments that felt more like a freewheeling conversation than a tightly scripted interview.</p>

<p>🔎 Three widely discussed moments</p>

<p>Below are the three parts of the episode that gained the most traction online. The summaries below paraphrase the discussion and avoid direct attribution of specific lines.</p>

<p>1) The future of work and AI</p>

<p>One theme was a futuristic projection about the role of human labour as AI and automation scale. The guest described a scenario where many routine economic tasks could be automated, leading to a world in which work as a necessity is reduced and creative or purposeful activity becomes more prominent for those who choose it.</p>

<p>Practical takeaway: the conversation underscores the importance of policy and social planning for transitions in labour markets, including retraining, social safety nets, and ways to preserve dignity and purpose.</p>

<p>2) India and talent</p>

<p>Another widely shared clip focused on India — both as a market and as a source of engineering talent. The discussion expressed strong praise for Indian engineers and noted connections between global engineering teams and India’s talent pool.</p>

<p>Practical takeaway: companies and policymakers can benefit from investing in education pathways, skills training and cross-border collaboration to make the most of global engineering talent.</p>

<p>3) Bureaucracy, immigration and efficiency</p>

<p>The episode also touched on immigration, visa systems and governmental efficiency. The guest critiqued certain aspects of administrative systems while also expressing support for attracting skilled talent. The conversation framed these issues as part of the broader challenge of improving institutional responsiveness.</p>

<p>Practical takeaway: better policy design, combined with transparent pathways for skilled migration, can improve economic dynamism while protecting workers and consumers.</p>

<p>🌐 The broader cultural moment</p>

<p>Why did this episode gain so much attention? Partly it’s the contrast: a high-profile entrepreneur speaking openly to a widely followed Indian host, producing soundbites that are easy to clip and share. On social platforms, short clips — especially those that touch on work, national pride or immigration — tend to travel quickly.</p>

<p>⚠️ Caveats and responsible sharing</p>

<p>This write-up is intentionally cautious. Public conversation often gets condensed into headlines and clips that lack context. If you plan to share or republish, I recommend linking to the full episode and avoiding paraphrases that turn back-of-the-envelope remarks into firm predictions.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><category term="podcasts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nikhil Kamath’s podcast People by WTF recently released an episode that quickly circulated across Indian social feeds: a long-form conversation with Elon Musk. The episode blends casual curiosity with philosophical digressions, and it offers several memorable moments that people have been discussing online.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/assets/images/blogs/wtf-musk-kamath-illustration.svg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/assets/images/blogs/wtf-musk-kamath-illustration.svg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The New GitHub Actions Pricing: What You Need to Know</title><link href="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/opinion/interviews/2025/12/16/musk-ramaswamy-interview-summary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The New GitHub Actions Pricing: What You Need to Know" /><published>2025-12-16T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-16T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/opinion/interviews/2025/12/16/musk-ramaswamy-interview-summary</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/opinion/interviews/2025/12/16/musk-ramaswamy-interview-summary.html"><![CDATA[<p>Recent changes GitHub announced for Actions pricing and platform fees.</p>

<p>✅ 1. The Good News: The Free Quota Remains the Same</p>

<p>The core free offering for individuals and small teams using the GitHub Free plan is unchanged:</p>

<p>Scenario
Free Quota
Private Repositories (GitHub Free)
2,000 minutes per month (using standard GitHub-hosted runners).
Public (Open Source) Repositories
Free and Unlimited (using standard GitHub-hosted runners).</p>

<p>If you are an individual developer or a small team using the minutes GitHub provides to run your CI/CD, you are not affected by the loss of your free minutes.</p>

<p>⚠️ 2. The Big Change: The New Platform Fee</p>

<p>GitHub is introducing a new fee for the underlying control plane (the service that orchestrates and manages the workflows), which previously was free for self-hosted users.</p>

<p>What is it? A $0.002 per-minute Actions cloud platform charge.</p>

<p>Who is affected? This charge applies primarily to private repositories using self-hosted runners.</p>

<p>Effective Date: This new fee will begin on March 1, 2026.</p>

<p>⚠️ Why is this a big deal?</p>

<p>Before this change, if you used your own server or cloud account (a self-hosted runner) to run your CI/CD, you only paid for your own compute. You paid $0 to GitHub for the orchestration. Now, you will pay the new $0.002/minute fee to GitHub for simply using their platform to run the workflow, even if the actual compute is on your machine.</p>

<p>💸 3. Price Reduction for Paid Users</p>

<p>To offset this change and improve the value of their product, GitHub is also reducing the cost of their standard GitHub-hosted runners by up to 39% for paid customers.</p>

<p>This price reduction goes into effect on January 1, 2026.</p>

<p>For GitHub-hosted runners, the new $0.002 platform charge is already included in the new, lower listed price.</p>

<p>📊 Summary Table of Impact</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Runner Type</th>
      <th style="text-align: right">Repository Type</th>
      <th style="text-align: right">Old Pricing to GitHub</th>
      <th style="text-align: right">New Pricing to GitHub (Mar 2026)</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>GitHub-Hosted</td>
      <td style="text-align: right">Private (Free Tier)</td>
      <td style="text-align: right">2,000 Minutes Free</td>
      <td style="text-align: right">2,000 Minutes Free</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>GitHub-Hosted</td>
      <td style="text-align: right">Public</td>
      <td style="text-align: right">Free &amp; Unlimited</td>
      <td style="text-align: right">Free &amp; Unlimited</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Self-Hosted</td>
      <td style="text-align: right">Private (All Tiers)</td>
      <td style="text-align: right">$0 per minute</td>
      <td style="text-align: right">$0.002 per minute platform fee</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="opinion" /><category term="interviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recent changes GitHub announced for Actions pricing and platform fees.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/assets/images/blogs/musk-ramaswamy-illustration.svg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pauljos.github.io/ssoulss/assets/images/blogs/musk-ramaswamy-illustration.svg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>